Ian Beihl

Full Stack Web Developer

After spending a few years in the Wyoming's beautiful Teton range, I moved to Oregon to continue my passion for living outdoors and building things. Whether creating complex craft cocktails as a seasoned bartender, outdoor furniture for our backyard, or fun and creative web apps, I love tinkering and building. As a kid I loved taking things apart, seeing how they worked, then putting them back together. Some things never change.



Personal Info

Address

1621 NW Hartford Bend, OR 97002

Phone

773-319-8778

E-mail

ianbeihl@gmail.com

Date of birth

1993-06-20

Portfolio

ianbeihl.com

LinkedIn

https://www.linkedin.com/in/ian-beihl-839b06b2/

GitHub

https://github.com/lbeihl



Skills

JavaScript

React/Redux

HTML5/CSS3

Node.js

Bootstrap

MongoDB

Mocha/Chai

Passport

Git/GitHub

Chrome Dev Tools

Heroku

Travis CI



Experience

2018-08 - Cocktail Buddy

present

- Created a cocktail recipe app that lets users search and filter a database of classic recipes as well as add and remove their own drinks.
- As an avid cocktail enthusiast, I wanted a way to easily search through and filter my favorite drink recipes while also having a place to store ones I have created or found elsewhere.
- Frontend: React/Redux
- Backend: Node.js, Express, Mongodb, Mongoose, JWT

2018-09 - Snow More Problems

present

- Built an app around World Weather Online's API that allows users to search and follow ski areas, compiling all their daily weather reports in one place.
- It is easy to look up one local snow report, but in the morning rush to get to the mountain, being able to easily check and compare reports from different ski areas is essential.
 - Frontend: React/Redux, Bootstrap
 - Backend: Node.js, Express, Mongodb, Mongoose, JWT

Education

2011-08 -

Bachelor of Arts in History, Colgate University

2015-05

- Major GPA: 3.37/4, GPA: 3.19, Dean's Award for Excellence Spring 2012
- Active member of Theta Chi Fraternity and Recruitment Chair in 2012.

Employment History

2018-06 - Full Stack Developer Apprenticeship

present

Thinkful, Brooklyn, NY (Remote)

- Learned industry best practices and standards with an emphasis on JavaScript, HTML5, Node.js, React, Redux, algorithms and data structures.
- Built mobile-first, responsive web applications while also meeting regularly with a senior web developer multiple times a week.

2017-09 - Front of House Staff

2018-05

Spork, Bend, OR

 Crafted well-balanced, delicious cocktails quickly and efficiently for the bar and entire restaurant while greeting and communicating with customers effectively.

2015-08 - Bartender

2017-05

The Rose and Pink Garter, Jackson, WY

• Created and added original craft cocktails to the menu, helping The Rose get the title of "Best Apres Ski Bar" from the cocktail review site, liquor.com.